[Music]
the exercise I'm about to show you is
called the lat pull down I call it
medicine for the malady what's the
malady everyday life and gravity pulling
us forward this medicine is going to get
us up better breathing better posture
feeling better feeling stronger let me
show you the move before we even get to
the bar we're going to get our feet
situated so that we pull forward we get
underneath these pads our shins are
against the pads that are down low we
push this top pad down far enough where
we feel pressure against the top of our
legs and our feet are stable in the
ground about hip width apart while I'm
here I'm going to make an adjustment
with my weight I will go light and get
it right we'll add strength and Reps
later just feel the movement first from
there we'll push back safely we're going
to grab our handle shoulder width apart
or where you're comfortable listen to
your shoulders because they're going to
tell you the truth fix your grip get a
nice hold we're going to come down under
control extend the arms let the weight
help us sit down softly when we're here
open the legs up so we can slide our
body forward and get secure in our pads
chin back chest up pull down elbows back
control up as high as we can go that's
the movement and if you're just starting
out 10 to 15 reps feeling your way
through it not rushing squeezing at the
bottom feeling your way all the way to
the top that's where you start just feel
it out now if you've done this before
you can increase weight you can drop
your reps you can switch your grip or
you can change your Tempo so here's how
that might look different I decide I'm
going to go 5 Seconds down feeling every
inch of this movement when I get to the
bottom I'm squeezing those shoulder
blades down and back like I'm trying to
crush a grape between my shoulder blades
and then I'm going to control back up 3
to 5 Seconds you're going to feel that
now here's the beauty of this if you
take the time to set it up and make it
your own it is going to help you stand
up feel great breathe better here's the
key if it gives you pain if it doesn't
feel right for you then like all
exercises it's not right for you but if
it is this one's a winner
[Music]